<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiliam V. Joaquim</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wiliam V. Joaquim</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 19:03:34 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Authentication with Golang and AWS Cognito</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/autenticacao-golang-cognito/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 19:03:34 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/autenticacao-golang-cognito/</guid>
      <description>What is cognito? The authentication of an application is something very important in the system, but also very sensitive, there are various implementations, security, validation to be considered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing SQL Injection with Golang</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/sql-injection-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 19:03:34 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/sql-injection-golang/</guid>
      <description>What will we cover? SQL injection is one of the most used techniques to carry out attacks on your system, where we can execute malicious SQL on vulnerable endpoints, making it possible to manipulate your database, although there are already many ways to mitigate this attack, it is still possible to leave this gap if the developer don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get control over your SQL with Golang and SQLC</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/golang-sqlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 17:11:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/golang-sqlc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Dealing with SQL often becomes complicated and tiring, dealing with so many queries, indexing, performance, security, transactions and everything that involves the use of SQL, with this in mind, the use of ORM is increasingly being adopted, aiming to make our lives easier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using migrations with Golang</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/migrations-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 17:00:30 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/migrations-golang/</guid>
      <description>What are migrations? Migrations are widely used to maintain version control of your database structure, it is a very useful solution for keeping your database organized.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of the CLI with Golang and Cobra CLI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/cobra-cli-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:40:41 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/cobra-cli-golang/</guid>
      <description>Today we are going to see all the power that a CLI (Command line interface) can bring to development, a CLI can help us perform tasks more effectively and lightly through commands via terminal, without needing an interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using contracts with NestJS, facilitating your unit tests</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/nestjs-contratos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 14:56:59 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/nestjs-contratos/</guid>
      <description>What are contracts? Contracts are a way of separating responsibilities between the parties that use this implementation, contracts are widely used in the context of software development following the DDD (Domain-Driven Design) standard.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
